So let's start implementing the burger builder component
imdi Bergere Boulder bileenini uygulamaya balayalm.
and as we identified in our design phase, this should actually be a container because there we plan on
Ve tasarm aamamzda tanmladmz gibi, aslnda bir konteynr olmaldr nk orada ina etmek
managing the state for the burger we're about to build.
zere olduumuz Newberger iin devleti ynetmeyi planlyoruz.
So I will go into the containers folder in the source folder and there I'll create a new subfolder
Bu yzden kaynak klasrndeki containers klasrne gideceim ve burger builder
which i'll name burger builder because that should be the component name.
adl yeni bir alt klasr oluturabiliyorlar nk bileen ad olacak.
So there I'll add a burgerbuilder.js file and in there I'm now going to create this component of
Dolaysyla hepsi burger Boulder dot js dosyasnda ve oradaki snf anahtar kelime ile elbette bu
course with the class keyword because I need to manage state in there later.
bileen oluturacam, nk orada daha sonra durumu ynetmek zorundaym.
I'll name it burger builder and I need to extend this component object
Burger kurucusunu yazacam ve bu bileen nesnesini geniletmem gerekiyor.
we can import from react.
Tepki vererek ie aktarabiliriz.
So let's add this import right away,
Bylece hemen ithalat yapalm.
let's also import react to be able to write jsx and then as a named import component from the
J'nin X olarak yazlabilmesi iin ithalatta tepki verenlerin hepsi bu ve ardndan Riak paketinden adlandrlm bir ithalat
react package.
bileeni olarak tepki veriyor.
This is our class definition finished,
Snf tanmmz bitti.
now as you learn, there is one important lifecycle method we need to implement, the render method.
Artk rendiiniz gibi render yntemini uygulamamz gereken nemli bir yaam dngs yntemi var.
This is a must because we must tell react what we want to render.
Bu arttr, nk oraya girmek istediimiz eyi yeniden hareket ettirmek zorundayz.
There, you need to return some jsx code and now the question of course is what do we want to return here?
Zahm GSX kodunu iade etmeniz gerekiyor ve imdi tabii ki soru u ki burada dnmek istiyoruz.
Now this will probably grow as we build this application,
imdi, bu uygulamay olutururken bu muhtemelen artacaktr.
for example we might also return a modal here conditionally if it's about time to show it.
rnein burada gstermek iin vaktimiz varsa koullu bir modl de dndrebiliriz.
But for now what I want to do is I want to render two different things and I will wrap it with a div
Ama imdilik yapmak istediim iki farkl ii yapmak istiyorum ve bunu bir div ile tamamlayacam.
here
imdilik aslnda biziz.
let's use our auxiliary component for that so
Yardmc bileenimizi bunun iin kullanalm.
let's quickly import aux from and then go up all the way to the source level hoc aux. Because
Hadi alks'leri hzla ieri aktaralm ve sonra kaynak seviyesine kadar ilerleyelim 0 alks'leri grelim nk gerekten
i don't really need a div now that I'm thinking about it,
dnmeye balam bir gne ihtiya duymuyorlar.
this does it, to simply fulfill the requirement of having a wrapping element. Because here I want to return
Sonunda bitiik bileenlere geri dnmek istediinizde sarma esinin olmas gerekliliini
two adjacent components in the end,
basite yerine getirmek iin yapar.
for now let's use divs as placeholders,
imdilik, farklar yer tutucu olarak kullanalm.
I want to return the burger I built
Ina ettiim Bergere'ye dnmek istiyorum.
so a graphical representation of the burger with all the ingredients and below that, I want to have
Bergere'nin tm ieriklerle birlikte grafik olarak gsterilmesi ve bunun
my build controls or something like that.
altnda kontrollerimi yaptrmam isterim.
So basically an area where I can add and remove ingredients, this is the setup I want to use.
Yani temelde katk pay ekleyip kaldrabildiim alan kullanacak bir tane kuruyor.
We might add more to this component
Bu bileene daha fazla katkda bulunabiliriz.
as I mentioned but this is the base setup of it.
Bahsettiim gibi, ancak bunun kurulu olduu temel budur.
So for now let me quickly export this class as a default of this file
Bu yzden imdi bu snf varsaylan bir ofis dosyas olarak hzl bir ekilde vereyim.
and let's now import the burger builder after saving it in your app.js file and replace test
Ve imdi Bergere yapmcsn, son sonbaharda sakladktan sonra ithal edelim ve testi onunla
with it.
deitirelim.
So there, I will import the burger builder from
Bylece orada burger yapcy ithal edeceim.
and now I need to go to the containers folder, to the burger builder folder and use the burgerbuilder.js file of
Ve imdi yapc klasr iin kapsayclar klasrne gitmem gerekiyor ve renirken elbette dosya
course without the file extension as you learned.
uzants olmadan burger oluturucu js dosyasn kullanmalym.
Burger builder can be a self-closing component,
Burger kurucu kendiliinden kapanan bir bileen olabilir.
I don't need to wrap any content with the selectors and after saving this, we should see burger and build
Seicilerle herhangi bir ierii sarmam gerekmiyor ve bunu kaydettikten sonra burger ve kabark
controls.
kontroller grmeliyiz.
Now I could understand if you're not totally flashed, this certainly can be improved from a styling perspective.
unu anlayabilirim ki, tamamen patlam iseniz, k bir perspektiften gelitirilebilir.
So first of all let's make sure that we have some margin between our toolbar even though it's just a
Her eyden nce, u anda sadece bir yer tutucu olmasna ramen ara ubuumuz arasnda bir miktar farkmz
placeholder right now
olduundan emin olalm.
and our other part and I will do this in the layout component because it's there where we have the
Ve dier blmmz ve bunu, yerleim bileeninde yapacaz nk orada ara ubuu iin alan
area for the toolbar, the area for the main part and I simply want to add a css class to the
ve ana blm iin alan var ve sadece burada ana eye Clarus
main element here to make sure that it has some margin. For that,
olarak bir dizi eklemek istiyoruz. bunun bir miktar marj olduunu syledi.
I will add a new file layout.css and in that file, I will create a new class and I'll name it content,
C S S yeni bir dosya dzeni ekleyeceim ve bu dosyada yeni bir snf oluturacam ve bir topal ierik ekleyeceim.
the name of course is totally up to you
Elbette ismi tamamen size kalm.
and there I'll add margin-top 16px.
st 16 piksel kenar boluu ekleyeceklerdir.
I will now go back to layout.js file and quickly import classes from this layout.css file and with
imdi LaChaise sonbaharna geri dneceim ve Colossus'u CSSA'nn sonbahar aylarnda hzl bir ekilde
that, we can go to the main element here, add class name and there assign classes content, like that.
ie aktaracam ve burada ana eye gidip snf ad ekleyip snf ierii atayamayacaz.
Now if we save this, we got some margin but still this doesn't exactly look like a burger.
imdi bunu kurtarrsak biraz marjmz var ama yine de bu tam olarak bir burger gibi grnmyor.
We can probably still increase that
Muhtemelen hala artabiliriz.
so as a next step let's add a burger component and the burger ingredients which actually should be rendered
sonraki adm olarak bir burger bileenini ve burger bileenlerini eklemeliyiz, bu da aslnda burada sunulmal.
there.
Bir